Hassan Ali

PhD Candidate, UNSW, Sydney

➤ hassan.ali@unsw.edu.au

Google Scholar

Sydney, Australia

(b) 0000-0002-1701-0390

hassanalikhatim

hassanalikhatim.github.io

How do I see myself?

I am a self-motivated machine learning engineer and researcher. As a researcher, I strive to enable real-world deployment of machine learning models that people can trust. As an engineer, My goal is to use my skills to assist people in their daily routine tasks.

Education

Sep 2023 – Ongoing

University of New South Wales (UNSW), Sydney, Australia

PhD in Computer Science and Engineering (Full-time)

• Research focuses on Trustworthy Machine Learning

Sep 2017 - Aug 2019

National University of Sciences and Technology (NUST), Islamabad, Pakistan

Master of Science in Electrical Engineering **(CGPA: 4.0/4.0)**

• <u>Thesis Title:</u> "Analyzing the Security Vulnerabilities of Deep Neural Networks: Attacks and Defenses"

Sep 2013 - Aug 2017

University of Engineering and Technology (UET), Lahore, Pakistan

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering (CGPA: 3.645/4.0)

Work Experience

Sep 2021 - Sep 2023

Information Technology University (ITU)

Research Assistant

• Human-centric Robust ML-driven IoT Smart Services

Jan 2021 - Nov 2021

Information Technology University (ITU)

Research Assistant

Mitigating Anti-social Behavior through Beneficial AI

Tools and skillset

- Python, PyTorch, TensorFlow (last 5 years)
- Java, C, MATLAB, Verilog, VHDL, HTML

Publications

2024

- 1. **Ali, H.**, Javed, R. T., Qayyum, A., AlGhadhban, A., Alazmi, M., Alzamil, A., Al-utaibi, K. & Qadir, J. Robust Encrypted Inference in Deep Learning: A Pathway to Secure Misinformation Detection. *IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing* (2024).
- 2. Butt, M. A., **Ali, H.**, Qayyum, A., Sultani, W., Al-Fuqaha, A. & Qadir, J. R²S100K: Road-Region Segmentation Dataset for Semi-supervised Autonomous Driving in the Wild. *International Journal of Computer Vision*, 1–19 (2024).
- 3. Al-Maliki, S., Qayyum, A., Ali, H., Abdallah, M., Qadir, J., Hoang, D. T., Niyato, D. & Al-Fuqaha, A. Adversarial Machine Learning for Social Good: Reframing the Adversary as an Ally. *IEEE Transactions on Artificial Intelligence* (2024).
- 4. Qayyum, A., Butt, M. A., **Ali, H.**, Usman, M., Halabi, O., Al-Fuqaha, A., Abbasi, Q. H., Imran, M. A. & Qadir, J. Secure and trustworthy artificial intelligence-extended reality (AI-XR) for metaverses. *ACM Computing Surveys* **56**, 1–38 (2024).

2023

- 5. **Ali, H.**, Butt, M. A., Filali, F., Al-Fuqaha, A. & Qadir, J. Consistent Valid Physically-Realizable Adversarial Attack Against Crowd-Flow Prediction Models. *IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems*, 1–16. doi:10.1109/TITS.2023.3343971 (2023).
- 6. **Ali, H.**, Khan, M. S., AlGhadhban, A., Alazmi, M., Alzamil, A., Al-Utaibi, K. & Qadir, J. Con-detect: Detecting adversarially perturbed natural language inputs to deep classifiers through holistic analysis. *Computers & Security* **132**, 103367 (2023).
- 7. Butt, M. A., Qayyum, A., **Ali, H.**, Al-Fuqaha, A. & Qadir, J. Towards secure private and trustworthy human-centric embedded machine learning: An emotion-aware facial recognition case study. *Computers & Security* **125**, 103058 (2023).

2022

8. **Ali, H.**, Khan, M. S., Al-Fuqaha, A. & Qadir, J. Tamp-X: Attacking explainable natural language classifiers through tampered activations. *Computers & Security* **120**, 102791 (2022).

2021

- 9. **Ali, H.**, Khan, M. S., AlGhadhban, A., Alazmi, M., Alzamil, A., Al-Utaibi, K. & Qadir, J. All your fake detector are belong to us: evaluating adversarial robustness of fake-news detectors under black-box settings. *IEEE Access* **9**, 81678–81692 (2021).
- 10. Petrick, N., Akbar, S., Cha, K. H., Nofech-Mozes, S., Sahiner, B., Gavrielides, M. A., Kalpathy-Cramer, J., Drukker, K., Martel, A. L. & BreastPathQ Challenge Group, f. t. SPIE-AAPM-NCI BreastPathQ Challenge: an image analysis challenge for quantitative tumor cellularity assessment in breast cancer histology images following neoadjuvant treatment. *Journal of Medical Imaging* 8, 034501–034501 (2021).

2020

11. Khalid, F., **Ali, H.**, Hanif, M. A., Rehman, S., Ahmed, R. & Shafique, M. FaDec: A Fast Decision-based Attack for Adversarial Machine Learning in 2020 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN) (2020), 1–8.

2019

- 12. **Ali, H.**, Khalid, F., Tariq, H. A., Hanif, M. A., Ahmed, R. & Rehman, S. SSCNets: Robustifying DNNs using Secure Selective Convolutional Filters. *IEEE Design & Test* **37**, 58–65 (2019).
- 13. Khalid, F., Ali, H., Tariq, H., Hanif, M. A., Rehman, S., Ahmed, R. & Shafique, M. QuSecNets: Quantization-based defense mechanism for securing deep neural network against adversarial attacks in 2019 IEEE 25th International Symposium on On-Line Testing and Robust System Design (IOLTS) (2019), 182–187.